Martin Petersilia Arts Collection 016
People's Archive, MLK Library
Martin Petersilia Arts Collection
1980-1989
People's Archive, MLK Library
Petersilia, Martin
016
1.5 Linear feet
4 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
Martin Petersilia was keenly interested in performing and visual arts, particularly those related to black artists and organizations. He was an employee and volunteer at many local arts organizations and collected numerous items related to the arts in D.C.
Custodial History
Martin Petersilia donated his collection of items related to artists and arts organizations to the D.C. Public Library in 1989.
Scope and Contents
Consists of programs, invitations, musical scores, correspondence, publicity, photographs, and clippings from arts organizations such as the Greg Reynolds Dance Quintet, The Women's Arts Center, Momentum Black Theater, and the Nubian League. Items from arts organizations appear first arranged alphabetically followed and then general information about the visual arts and artists in Washington. Oversized materials are in a separate box.
Related Materials
See the Greg Reynolds Dance Quintet Records, 022
Arts; Performing Arts; Photographs; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc); Correspondence; Ephemera; Photographs; Sheet music
- Series 1
  - Artists in School Program, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Arts Publicity, 1972-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ethiopian Artists Program, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Greg Reynolds Dance Quintet, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Greg Reynolds Dance Quintet, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Greg Reynolds Dance Quintet, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Greg Reynolds Dance Quintet, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Greg Reynolds Dance Quintet, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Lansburgh Cultural Center, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Metropolitan Dance Association, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Momentum Dance Theater, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Nubian League - photographs, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Nubian League - photographs - general, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Nubian League - photographs - Festival of Black Storytelling, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Washington Area film Video League Newsletter, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Women's Art Center, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Women's Art Center, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Women's Art Center, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Women's Art Center, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Women's Art Center, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Women's Art Center, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Women's Art Center, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Women's Art Center, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Visual Arts, 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Visual Arts, 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Visual Arts, 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Visual Arts, 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Visual Arts, 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Visual Arts, 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Printmakers Reception flyer, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Hartigan exhibit catalog, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Gallery Museum News, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - YWCA Arts Fall Season Flyer, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)